<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Grading on HIST1900A</title>
    <link>/tags/grading/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Grading on HIST1900A</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <atom:link href="/tags/grading/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Assessment</title>
      <link>/docs/assessment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs/assessment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;entrance-tickets&#34;&gt;Entrance Tickets&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;These are ungraded responses to prompts that I will use to kick-off discussions. On days with an &amp;rsquo;entrance ticket&amp;rsquo;, you will have jotted a quick response on a notecard before class (and you&amp;rsquo;ll have printed your name on it too). I will collect these at the start of class. Their &lt;em&gt;completion&lt;/em&gt; however will count towards your &amp;lsquo;academic presence&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;hypothesis&#34;&gt;Hypothes.is&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hypothesis is a tool to hone your academic reading skills. Sustained meaningful activity there on the assigned readings counts towards your &amp;lsquo;academic presence&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>General Philosophy</title>
      <link>/docs/general-philosophy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs/general-philosophy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-most-important-idea&#34;&gt;The Most Important Idea&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The internet is an emergent &lt;em&gt;thing&lt;/em&gt; at the intersection of power, energy, information, materials, and humans.&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Always: humans.&lt;/strong&gt;  An archaeological perspective on this pays attention to entanglements and flows. And if we apply the appropriate lenses to how we look, we might begin to understand &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Spend some time with Kate Crawford&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://knowingmachines.org/publications/calculating-empires&#34;&gt;Calculating Empires&lt;/a&gt; to see what I mean (you&amp;rsquo;ll want to open this in a new browser window; try taking the audio tour, too).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Syllabus</title>
      <link>/docs/first-things-first/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs/first-things-first/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;According to section 2 of FASS Undergraduate Teaching Regulations and Procedures, this course outline constitutes a contract between you the student, and me, the professor. However, the word ‘syllabus’ (aka, the course outline), it seems is based on a misreading of a misprint of the Greek word ‘sittybis’, meaning a table of contents. A table of contents is not a contract. Nevertheless, let us have a contract thus:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I, Professor Graham, agree to undertake to the best of my abilities, the task of challenging, guiding, and fostering in you, a deeper appreciation, awareness, and understanding for the ideas discussed in this class. You, for your part, agree to undertake the necessary intellectual work to meet me halfway, bringing your best abilities to bear, endeavouring to be receptive and prepared for all course-related activities. Together, we agree to create a community of learning and practice, such that true learning may occur.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
