<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Submit on HIST1900A</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/tags/submit/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Submit on HIST1900A</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/tags/submit/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>FAQ</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/docs/faq/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/docs/faq/</guid>
      <description>FAQ &amp;amp; Helpful Hints Workbench? Content? JupyterLab? What? There are two interconnected components to this course.&#xA;This website: it is the overarching context for what I am trying to teach you re digital archaeology. It specifies what to read and listen and do each week. Most of the time, when I want you to do something, it will be at your workbench. The workbench. The workbench is made of two things: a.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Syllabus</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/docs/first-things-first/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/docs/first-things-first/</guid>
      <description>According to section 2 of FASS Undergraduate Teaching Regulations and Procedures, this course outline constitutes a contract between you the student, and me, the professor. However, the word ‘syllabus’ (aka, the course outline), it seems is based on a misreading of a misprint of the Greek word ‘sittybis’, meaning a table of contents. A table of contents is not a contract. Nevertheless, let us have a contract thus:&#xA;I, Professor Graham, agree to undertake to the best of my abilities, the task of challenging, guiding, and fostering in you, a deeper appreciation, awareness, and understanding for the ideas discussed in this class.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
