<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Notetaking on HIST1900A</title>
    <link>/tags/notetaking/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Notetaking on HIST1900A</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2025 12:27:21 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/notetaking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A Research Memo &amp; Précis</title>
      <link>/docs/a-research-memo-pr%C3%A9cis/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs/a-research-memo-pr%C3%A9cis/</guid>
      <description>Some of our in-class work will be devoted to crafting research memos that use the rhetorical précis as formulated by the historian Chad Black.&#xA;courtesy of Chad Black, quoted in full below with a few small friendly amendments&#xA;The Rhetorical Précis is a formula designed to help you move beyond simple summary to a more analytical synopsis of a work. As such, the précis, in a compact form, forces you to think about both the content and method of a piece of scholarship.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On Essays</title>
      <link>/docs/on-essays/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs/on-essays/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;ve been practicing taking research memos, if you&amp;rsquo;ve been looking at our feedback and thinking about what I or the TAs have said, you are already 9/10s of the way to writing an essay that can critically examine some issue, backed up with meaningful scholarly insight.&#xA;Yes! It&amp;rsquo;s true!&#xA;Note Making IS Writing The secret to academic writing is that your notes have already done a lot of the thinking for you.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Read Like An Academic</title>
      <link>/docs/read-like-an-academic/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs/read-like-an-academic/</guid>
      <description>Reading an academic article is not like &amp;lsquo;regular&amp;rsquo; reading. You don&amp;rsquo;t start at the beginning and wait for the big reveal at the end. (You don&amp;rsquo;t write like that either.)&#xA;Read Like A Predator Read like a predator. You&amp;rsquo;re after something. Each time your read the paper, you&amp;rsquo;re after something different.&#xA;First time: just the abstract, maybe the intro Second time: intro, conclusion Third time: discussion, conclusion Fourth time: methods What you&amp;rsquo;re doing is a kind of triage.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THOMAS</title>
      <link>/docs/thomas/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs/thomas/</guid>
      <description>Reading Historical Scholarship¶ Reading historical scholarship is not just about understanding the content, but also figuring out how the thing you&amp;rsquo;re reading is part of a broader dialogue. Allow me to introduce a useful approach to reading such material by Danna Agmon called &amp;lsquo;THOMAS&amp;rsquo;. I quote Agmon directly below:&#xA;THOMAS: A Useful Mnemonic for Reading Historical Scholarship&#xA;When reading works of historical scholarship, the following mnemonic is a helpful tool to keep in mind as you prepare for class.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zotero</title>
      <link>/docs/zotero/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs/zotero/</guid>
      <description>Zotero instructions go here.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
